**
不好意思... 对不起
I'm sorry... Sorry
没事儿 坐那
No, Stay
你叫什么？
What's your name?
安德鲁·内曼
Andrew Neyman.
几年级？
What year are you?
大一
I'm... a first year
知道我是谁么
You know who I am?
知道
Yes sir.
所以你知道我在找乐手
So you know I'm looking for players?
知道
Yes sir.
那你怎么不打了
Then why did you stop playing?
我让你再接着打了么
Did I ask you to start playing again?
-不好意思我以为..  -我问你怎么不打了你跟公仔猴似的坐那是什么意思？
-Ugh, I'm sorry... -I asked you why did you stop playing and your version of an answer was to turn into a wind-up monkey
-对不起.. -给我看看基本功
-I'm.. I'm sorry  -Show me your rudiments.
-好的
Yes sir.
双倍摇摆
Double time swing
双倍 双起来
No double time, double it
快点
Faster
Faster!
哎哟 忘拿外套了
Woopsy-daisy, forgot my jacket.
不要炸鱼了吗
No Swedish Fish?
今天不用了
Not today.
谢谢
Thanks.
-你没事吧？ -没事啊
-You ok?  -Yeah
哎 他今天看到我练鼓了
Yeah, I don't know. He saw me play today.
然后呢？
And?
你可走的路多着呢
You got plenty of options still.
什么意思 什么路？
What does that mean? Other options?
就是...
Just.. You know.
这就是人生
It's just life.
等你到了我这年纪 你就不会钻牛角尖了
You get to be my age, you get perspective.
我就想要钻牛角尖
I don't want perspective
抱歉
Sorry.
我不想要葡萄干
I don't want raisin in it.
那怎么不早说
Why didn't you say that?
我绕着吃就好了
I just eat around them.
真不懂你
I don't understand you.
操这是谁啊瑞安
My man Ryan, yo shit!
多久没见了
How you feeling man?
内曼那鼓打的太糟心了
Things were hurting with Neyman on the kits.
Hey内曼 周末怎么样啊
Hey what's up bro. Had a good weekend?
挺好的 特开心
Yeah real good. Lot of fun.
别理格雷格 他就是嘴贱
Hey, don't worry about Greg. He's a dick.
没事
No big deal.
早上好
Good morning everybody.
早 上 好
早上好...
Morning.
嗯 先来Billy's Ann 从头起 没问题吧？
Alright. Let's do Billy's Ann, from the top, yes?
1 2 3 走
One Two Three
好了换Reese
Alright let's do... Reese
瑞安
Yo Ryan
巴迪.瑞奇
行啦  行啦
Alright alright.
先到这吧换回核心鼓手
That's enough for that, just back to the core drummer please.
核心乐手 准备
Core players, let's go.
你这两天都练什么呢
Dude, what've you been practicing?
不介意吧？
May I?
真幼齿
Cute.
下面那行 小号 78小节
Down the line, trumpets, bar 78.
三四
Three Four
好了
Ok, alright.
24小节 最后两拍开始
the bar 24, the end of two.
算了不用了
Maybe not.
211小节开始 三四
Let's pick up on 211, Three Four.
一样 三四
Same spot, three four.
行了
Alright.
你是首席 来看看是不是靠脸蛋儿坐到这的
You're in the first chair, let's see if it's just because you are cute.
三四
Three Four.
嗯果然是
Yeah, that's why.
鼓手 来试试双倍摇摆
Drums, let's hear a little double-time swing.
后面那个
Behind?
一样
Same thing.
贝司 之后5小节
Bass, five bars down the lead
就这样吧
Alright.
鼓手 跟我走
Drums, with me.
谢了 乔
Thank you Joe
不是你 叫他呢
No no no, other drums.
B16房间 明早6点
Room B16, tomorrow morning 6am
别迟到
Don't be late.
好了大家 从头开始
Alright everybody, from the top.
一二三
One Two Three
Hey 怎么样啊
Hey  How are you?
挺好的 你呢
Good, how are you?
好着呢 谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
老一套？
The usual?
嗯 我不大了解一般... 怎么...
Ugh... Nah, Look I don't know how...
我经常在这看到你 我觉得你很漂亮
I see you here a lot, and I think you are... really pretty.
你愿意跟我约会么？
Would you want go out with me... ever?
请走开
Please go away.
哦天啊 真对不起... 对不起
Oh my god. I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
我逗你呢 逗你呢
I'm just messing with you. I'm messing with you.
哦天啊
Oh my god.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不能这么欺负人啊
That's actually pretty mean
-对不起 你叫什么 -没关系啦
-I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.. what's your name? -No big deal.
-哦我叫安德鲁  -哦安德鲁
-Oh I'm Andrew.   -Andrew
我叫妮可
I'm Nicole
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you Nicole.
嗯我也是
Nice to meet you too.
所以你想约我出去？
So you wanna take me out?
我很想约你出去
I'd... love to take you out.
-去哪儿？ -匹萨
-Where you wanna go?  -Pizza.
-匹萨 我喜欢匹萨 -嗯 我知道一家很好的匹萨店
-Pizza. I like pizza.  -Yeah I know a great pizza place.
好
Cool, well...
我周一晚上7点下班
I get off at 7 on Monday.
哦是吗？
Okay?
-你想在这见么 -噢对 是是到时候我来找你
-You wanna meet here.. -Oh ok, yeah, I will.
好
Great
-嗯 那就7点？
-Ok. Seven o'clock?
-嗯 在这见 -7点
-Here   -7pm
-周一  -嗯 拜
-Monday   -Alright, bye.
你是新替补么
-You are the new alternate?
嗯 我叫安德鲁.内曼
-Yeah, I'm Andrew Neyman.
鼓调到降B调 排练的时候给我翻乐谱
-Tune  the set to a B-flat and turn my pages during rehearsal
没问题
Sure
抱歉 能给个降B调么？
Excuse me, can you give me a B-flat?
谢谢
Thank you.
不好意思 再来下可以么？
Sorry, can you... just one more time?
这鼓架真好
It's a great kit.
逼加紧了！
Milk the cunt!
新来了个小毛孩
We got a squeaker today people.
内曼 19岁
Neyman, 19 years old
可爱吧
isn't he cute?
好了同志们 Whiplash
Alright gang, "Whiplash"
翻页
Page.
翻页！
Page!
巴克 那不是你男朋友的鸡巴 别赶着高潮
Barker, that is not your boyfriend's dick, do not come early.
93小节
Bar 93
五六七走
Five Six and..
停！
Stop!
这个很让我郁闷 有人跑调了
Now this one really upsets me. We have an out-of-tone player here.
在我们继续前 跑掉的能先站出来么
Before I continue, would that player care to identify himself?
没人？那可能是我耳朵进虫子了
No? Ok, maybe a bug flew in my ear.
115小节
五六七走
Five Six and..
嗯 我耳朵很好 是有一个跑调的
No, my ears are fine, we definitely have an out-of-tone player.
不管你是谁 这是你最后的机会
Whoever it is, this is your last chance.
好吧你错过了
And there it went.
要么你是故意跑调拖乐队后腿
Now either you are deliberately playing out-of-tone and sabotaging my band
要么你自己都不知道自己跑调了
Or you don't know you are out-of-tone
那恐怕就更糟了
which I'm afraid is even worse.
五六七走
Five Six and..
号
Bones
五六七走
Five Six and..
就在这
He's here.
别给我说不是你 大头儿子
Tell me it's not you, Elmer Fudd.
没关系 吹吧
It's ok. Play.
你觉得自己跑调了么
Do you think you are out of tone?
你看什... 地上又没巧克力你看什么看
What're you... There's no fucking Mars bar down there, what are you looking at?
抬起头 看着我
Look up here, look at me.
你觉得 自己跑调了么
Do you think, you are out of tone?
跑了
Yes.
那你他妈的不吭声？！
Then why the fuck didn't you say so?!
梅茨你这死胖子在这待太久了
I carried your fat ass for too long Metz
我不能让一每天就知道惦记着儿童套餐不顾音调的傻逼毁了比赛
I'm not gonna have you cost us a competition because your mind's on a fucking Happy Meal instead of on pitch.
恭喜杰克逊 你是四席了
Jackson congratulations, you are fourth chair.
梅茨你还傻坐着干嘛呢 滚蛋啊
Mets why are you still sitting there, get the fuck out!
说明下 梅茨没跑调
For the record, Mets wasn't out of tone
跑调的是你 埃里克森
You were, Ericson
但是他自己都不知道
But he didn't know.
那已经够糟了
And that's bad enough.
休息10分钟 回来后小毛孩上
Alright take 10, when we get back the squeaker is on.
安德鲁
Andrew
爸妈是搞音乐的么
Parents are musicians?
不是
No
做什么的
What do they do?
我爸是个作家
My dad's a writer.
写什么的？
Oh what's he written
主要还是当老师了
I guess he's more of a teacher. Really.
大学？
Oh. College?
彭宁顿中学
Pennington High School.
你妈呢 她是干什么的
What about your mother? What does she do?
我不知道 很小时候她就离开了
I don't know. She left when I was a baby.
所以家里没有做音乐的？
So no musicians in the family?
那就多听经典吧
Well you just gotta listen to the greats then.
巴迪.瑞奇 乔.琼斯
Buddy Rich, Jo Jones
你知道查理.帕克成为“大鸟” 是因为当初乔.琼斯拿着钹往他脑袋上砸
You know Charlie Parker became Bird because Jo threw a cymbal at his head
懂我意思么？
See what I'm saying?
关键在于放松
Listen, the key is to just... relax.
别担心曲子 别担心别人怎么想
Don't worry about the numbers, don't worry about what the other guys are thinking.
你能来这是有原因的
You are here for a reason.
你相信这个吧
You believe that right?
嗯
Yeah.
说
Say it.
我能来这是有原因的
I'm here for a reason.
好
Cool
行了哥们儿 好好玩吧
Alright man, have fun.
同志们 Whiplash
Alright gang, Whiplash
节奏放慢点 内曼
A little under tempo ok? Neyman.
尽力就好
Just do your best.
开始
There you go.
五六七走
Five Six and...
来点带感的
Let's hear some feels.
巴迪.瑞奇化身啊
We got Buddy Rich here.
有点问题
A little trouble there.
17小节
Pick it up on 17
五六七走
Five Six and
节奏不大对
Not quite my tempo.
开始 五六七走
Here we go. Five Six and..
18 开始
Down beat on 18. Here we go.
五六七走
Five Six and...
17小节最后4拍
Bar 17 the end of four.
五六七走
Five Six Seven...
节奏不大对
Not quite my tempo.
没关系慢慢来
It's all good, no worries, here we go.
五六七走
Five Six Seven
赶了 再来
You're rushing. Here we go.
好了？
Ready?
五六七走
Ok. Five Six and...
有点拖
Dragging. Just here.
等我提示
Wait for my cue.
五六七走
Five Six Seven..
赶了
Rushing.
五六七走
Five Six and..
拖了
Dragging.
五六七走
Five Six and...
知道我为什么朝你扔椅子么
Why do you suppose I just hurled a chair at your head, Neyman?
我... 不知道
I.. I don't know.
你知道
Sure you do.
节奏？
The tempo?
你是赶了还是拖了？
Were you rushing or were you dragging?
我...不知道
I... I don't know.
开始数数
Start counting.
-五六 -从四开始！操 看着我
-Five Six..  -In 4 damnit! Look at me!
一二三四 一二三四 一二三四
One two three four One two three four One two three four
我是赶了还是拖了？
Now, was I rushing or was I dragging?
不...知道
I don't know.
再来
Count again.
一二三四 一二三四 一二三四
One two three four One two three four One two three four
-赶了还是拖了？  -赶了
-Rushing or dragging?  -Rushing.
所以你知道区别！
So you do know the difference!
你要敢故意给我拖后腿 我他妈逼的干死你
If you deliberately sabotage my band, I'll fuck you like a pig.
所以你是要赶 还是要拖
Now are you a rusher, or are you a dragger
还是跟我节奏来？！
Or are you gonna be on my fucking time?!
我跟你节奏来
I'll be on your time.
这上面写的什么
What does that say?
-四分音符等于215 -数个215给我看看
-Quarter note equals 215   -Count me a 215.
一二三四 一二三四
One two three four One two three four
我操他妈的 谢尔佛什么时候开始收智障了？
Jesus fucking Christ, I don't know they allow retards into Shaffer.
你是想告诉我你读不懂节拍么？
Am I to understand you cannot read tempo?
他妈的不会连谱都不识吧？
Can you even fucking read music?
那是什么？
What is that?
对 那是什么？
Yes, what is that?
附点十六分音符
A dotted sixteenth
给我哼下101小节
Sing me a measure 101
我操你他妈是清唱团的么？打鼓啊！
What are you, in a fucking acapella group? Play the goddamn kit!
停！
Stop!
现在给我说
Now answer my question.
你是赶了还是拖了？
Were you rushing, or were you dragging?
说话！
Answer!
赶了
Rushing.
我靠...
Oh my dear god.
你是要玩独泪无痕么？
Are you one of those single tear people?
一看我的脸你就高潮了是么？
Do I look like a double fucking rainbow to you?
-你一定很难受吧 你难受么？  -不难受
-You must be upset. Are you upset?   -No
不难受 所以你根本就不当回事？
No. So you just don't give a shit about any of this?
-我当回事  -那你倒是说话啊 难受还是他妈的不难受？
-I do give a shit... -So are you upset, yes or fucking no?
-难受 -你难受
-Yes -You are upset.
嗯
Yeah
说出来
Say it.
我难受
I'm upset.
大声点让大家都能听到
Say it to the whole band can hear you.
我难受
I'm upset.
大声点
Louder.
我难受
I'm upset.
大声点！
Louder!
我难受！
I'm upset!
你就是个没前途没朋友没价值的娘炮软逼
You are a worthless friendless faggot-lipped little piece of shit
小时候你妈发现跟错了人扔下你和你爸走了
Whose mommy left daddy, when she figured out he wasn't Eugene O'neil
长大了跑到老子鼓架上
And who's now weeping and slobbering all over my drum set
跟他妈小姑娘似的哭鼻子抹眼泪
like a fucking nine-year-old girl
我他妈的再说最后一次：大声点！
So for the final father fucking time... Say it louder!!!
我难受！
I'm upset!!
卡尔
Carl.
再努力点吧内曼
Start practicing harder Neyman
Whiplash 125小节
Whiplash, bar 125.
成年人节奏
Big boy tempo
五六七走
Five six and...
“少壮不努力，长大玩摇滚”
这地方不错
This place is nice.
嗯
Yeah
我喜欢他家放的音乐
I really liked the music that they play.
东西也好吃 不过...
I mean the food is good too, but...
嗯匹萨很棒
The pizza is really good.
当我醒来
When I wake.
什么？
What?
这首歌的名字
That's the name of the song.
杰基.希尔 1938年7月17
Jacky Hill, July 17th, 1938
鼓手是鲍勃.埃里森
Bob Ellis on the drums.
每次在电影院看到你的时候
You know every time I saw you at the theater
你眼睛都死盯着地板
Your eyes were glued to the floor.
是么？
Really?
我爸说我不知道怎么跟人做眼神接触
My dad says that I have trouble making eye contact.
我爸妈也爱挑我毛病
My parents like to criticize me too.
小时候我妈说我下巴很大
When I was growing up my mom said that I had a really big chin.
所以男生都不喜欢我
And that's why guys don't like me
-真的？  -是啊
-Really?   -Yeah.
-没有啊 -她说都是我爸咒的
-You don't.  -Well she said my dad curse me with one.
-哪里有  -有的
-No it's not.   -Yeah it is.
我一点没觉得
I don't... I don't think so at all.
你的下巴很... 漂亮
Your chin is very... nice.
很漂亮
Very nice.
你妈疯了吧哈哈
Your mom sounds insane.
嗯她在我这么大的时候倒是一直想当演员
Well she did want to be an actress when she was my age.
你呢
What about you?
我？
What about me?
你现在做什么呢？
What do you do?
我在福特汉姆上学
I go to Fordham.
学什么呢？
What do you study?
我还没有专业呢
I don't... have a major yet.
那你想学什么？
...like what do you want to study?
不知道
I don't really know.
还不知道呢
I don't know yet.
所以说福特汉姆就是随手挑的？
So Fordham was just like a random school?
也不是 我申请了一堆学校 福特汉姆录了我
No I've applied a bunch of schools, Fordham let me in.
那你为什么去谢尔佛？
Why do you go to Shaffer?
因为那是全国最好的音乐学院
It's the best music school in the country.
那..  福特汉姆就是福特汉姆而已了
Well Fordham is Fordham.
说实话我一点不喜欢那
I don't love there to be honest.
-不喜欢？  -不喜欢
-No?  -No.
不知道... 就觉得那边的人都不喜欢我
I don't know... I guess it's just people there don't like me very much.
我家是亚利桑那的 我觉得他们能...
I'm from Arizona, and I think they can...
看出来
see it.
嗯我在谢尔佛也是这感觉
I kinda feel the same way about people in Shaffer.
我觉得他们也不... 那么喜欢我
Yeah I don't think they like me too much.
但是我... 我...
But I don't...
我也不大在意
I don't care too much.
我觉得人都会... 变得嘛
I think it's just... it changes.
人变了... 也就没事了
You know people change, things work out.
嗯我懂你意思
Yeah I know I know I know.
我只是...
I just...
有时候挺想家的
I feel like homesick sometimes.
不知道...
I don't know.
就是挺受不了大家都装自己不想家
Kind pissed me off when people pretend like they are not.
大学么...
In college, you know.
也可能我真的是唯一一个想家的吧
Maybe I'm literally the only one, I don't know.
我到现在还跟我爸一起看电影呢
I still go to the movies with my dad.
Hey 最近怎么样啊
Hey how are you man.
挺好的
Good.
哈哈 这真的是Eva么？
Is this really Eva?
哇奥 上次见你你还那么小呢
Wow, last time I saw you you were very tiny.
开始练乐器了吗
Are you playing an instrument yet?
她上周开始练钢琴了
She started piano last week.
等你上了大学
Hey when you are a big college kid
来我乐队吧
Will you come and play in my band?
-想去吗？ -当我的钢琴师吧
-Do you like that? -Would you be my piano player?
太棒了 那就一言为定啦
Excellent, give me five
-嗯见到你很高兴 -见到你很高兴
-Alright, great seeing you. -Great seeing you.
表演完见吧 回聊
See you after the show. Alright cheers.
听好了小鸡巴崽子们
Listen up cocksuckers!
动作麻利点
Hurry the fuck up.
拿好乐谱
Get your music.
第一支曲目
节奏乐器组先出
Rhythm Section out first
坦纳 鼓架的音调简直他妈的惨不忍睹
Tanner, the kit is a fucking tonal catastrohpy
赶紧给我弄好了
Get it in tone alright?
节奏組和独奏部分 45小节
Rhythm and soloists, bar 45
节奏跟上了
we gonna pick up the tempo there alright?
106小节 管乐 别忘了音调再高半音
Bar 106, brass, do not forget we sharp that knife.
都给我记清楚了 林肯中心什么的都会用这场比赛作参考决定要谁不要谁
Everybody remember, Lincoln Center and its ilk use these competitions to decide who they are interested in and who they are not
我决不允许自己的名声
And I am not gonna have my reputation in that department tarnished
毁在你们这群阳痿早泄找不到音比你女朋友还他妈软逼的小儿麻痹手上
by a bunch of fucking limp-dick, sour-note, flattered on their girlfriend's flexible tempo dipshits.
懂？
Got it?
另外 尤金 给我递过来
One more thing. Eugene give me that.
如果我再看到有人到处乱扔谱子
If I ever find another one of these lying around again
我他妈逼的保证我不会再这么客气了
I swear to fucking god I will stop being so polite.
你他妈的有多远滚多远不然爷灭了你
Get fuck out of my sight before I demolish you.
整理好了 准备上台
Stage right, in order, now.
我还是能看到你 小挫逼！
I can still fucking see you, Mini-Me!
动作快点 等什么呢你
Let's go, hurry the fuck up. Let's go.
谢尔佛音乐学院 音乐室乐队
Shaffer Conservatory, Studio Band.
给我拿着 下场演出给我
Hold onto this for the second set.
...他想在这做职业乐手
I think he wants a career
但是有弗莱彻在这他压根没法回来
But as long as Fletcher is here, Fudd don't have a chance get back in..
给我看下谱子
I need to look at the music.
哦在这呢
Oh yeah it's right here.
你怎么不拿在手上？
Why isn't it on you?
谱子呢？
Where's the folder?
-你逗我呢吧  -我不...
-You're joking right?  -I have no.. No I literally
我真的... 我发誓刚刚还在这呢
No.. I swear I just had it here two seconds ago
肯定就在附近
It's gotta be around here.
-你他妈脑子进屎了么 -是不是清洁工过来...
-How could you be so fucking stupid? -I don't know, maybe a janitor came bay or something..
-清洁工？ -嗯
-A janitor?  -Yeah
给我找谱子去！他妈的清洁工？
-Find the fucking folder! A fucking janitor?!
你他妈完了！操！
You are done! Fuck!
我他妈完了！操！
I'm done! Fuck!
-找谱子去！  -对不起
-Find the folder!  -I'm sorry.
坦纳!
Tanner!
我操你去哪玩了？
Jesus fucking Christ, where have you been??
出了点问题..
We have an issue..
哦 现在不是时候
Ok, now is not the time.
我...把谱子给了内曼 内曼搞丢了
I gave... Neyman the folder and Neyman lost it.
内曼搞丢了？
Neyman lost it?
嗯
Yes.
谱子是你的责任
The folder is your fucking responsibility, Tanner
你他妈给内曼干嘛？
Why would you give it to Neymon, right?
你让智障帮你拿计算器 他能当成遥控拿去开电视
You gave a calculator to a fucking retard he's gonna try turn on the TV with it.
拿好鼓槌滚上台去
Now get your stick and get your ass on the stage
我..不行
I... I can't
你..不行？
You.. can't?
我上不了台... 我谱子没背过
I can't go on stage, I don't know the charts.. by heart.
你他妈逗我呢？
Are you fucking kidding me?
我是... 我... 你知道啊
I.. you know this.
我需要谱子 那是我视觉提示物
I need the music, it's my memory, I need visual cues.
-视觉提示物？  -有这种健康问题
-Visual cues?  -It's a medical condition..
健康问题？你他妈以为自己是舟舟啊？给我打鼓去!
Medical condition? What are you, fucking Sunjay Gupta? Play the goddamn music!
-我真不行 -我行
-I can't -I can.
你背过Whiplash的谱子了？
You know Whiplash by heart?
背过了 每个拍子都记得
Yes sir, every measure.
好吧 你最好祈祷你记得够清楚
Alright. You better fucking hope your memory doesn't fail you
并且比上次排练的时候打的好很多
And and you can play a whole lot better than you did last month at the rehearsal
我可不准备现在就卷铺盖回家
Because I do not intend start losing now.
拿好槌子滚上台去
Get your stick and get your fucking ass on the stage.
上台！
On stage!
第一名
And first place
谢尔佛音乐学院
Shaffer Conservatory
别碰我谱子啊
Don't touch my folder man.
别碰我鼓架
Do not touch this kit.
好了开工吧女士们
Alright let's get to work ladies.
坦纳你来干嘛了 今天是核心排练 没时间调教替补
Tanner what are you doing? It's core only today, I don't have time for alternates.
Cherokee 从头开始
Cherokee, from the top.
你他妈是雕像么 动啊
Tanner are you a fucking statue? Let's go!
别傻坐着
Get off the stool.
别忘了给内曼翻乐谱
Don't forget to turn Neyman's pages.
准备 一二三四 二二三四
Here we go, one two three four two two three four
妮可：回来以后给我电话，我过去找你？
音乐室乐队怎么样了？
So how's everything going with the Studio Band?
挺好的 我觉得他越来越喜欢我了
Good. I think he likes me more now.
他的看法对你很重要是吧
And his opinion means a lot to you, doesn't it?
嗯
Yeah
帮我端下菜
这菜快糊了哎
overcooked.
嚼不动嘛
can barely chew this
他刚走
He just left.
安迪 鼓打的怎么样啦
So how's drumming going Andy?
嗯特好 我是新核心鼓手了
Yeah it's going really well. I'm the new core drummer...
-你听说了么？ -没 怎么了？
-Did you hear yet?  -No, what happened?
特拉维斯拿了最有价值球员
Travis just got MVP
牛逼啊！
That's fantastic!
达斯汀进模拟联合国了 很快就能拿罗德学者奖学金啦
Dustin is heading up Model UN, soon-to-be-Rhodes-Scholar and who knows what
吉姆还是年度教师
And Jim, teacher of the year
真的 这一家子都是天赋异禀啊
I mean, come on, the talent of this table, that is stunning.
哦还有安迪 打鼓
And Andy, with your drumming.
还行吧安迪?
It's going ok, Andy?
嗯特别 特别好
Yeah I mean it's going really, really well.
我进了谢尔佛学院最好的爵士乐团
Actually I'm part of Shaffer's top Jazz orchestra
也就是是全国最顶尖的
Which means I'm.. it's the best in the country.
我还是核心乐手 跟着乐队到处比赛
And.. I'm a core member, so I just started playing competitions
前两天发现自己还是全乐队最小的
Actually I just found out I'm the youngest person in the entire band.
音乐比赛怎么算赢？应该都是主观感受吧
How do you know wins or not.. a music competition? Isn't it subjective?
不是
No.
音乐室给你工作么？
Does the studio get you a job?
不是那种音乐室 “音乐室”只是乐队的名字
No it's not an actual studio, it's just the name of the ensemble
但这对我的职业生涯帮助很大
but yeah it's a big step for my career.
嗯干得不错就好 我们都知道这行很乱
Well I'm so glad you figured it out, it's a nasty business I am sure.
哦对了 赶快给我们讲讲这礼拜的球赛！
Oh are you gonna tell them about your game this week?
什么叫名副其实！
Lived up to your title
我推了93码达阵
I scored 93 yard touchdown
学校新纪录啊
School record, school record!
那是三区的球队
It's division III.
卡尔顿的校队么 三区的 连二区都没进呢
It's Carleton football, it's not even division II, it's division III
你有朋友么安迪
You got any friends Andy?
-没有  -为什么？
-No. -Why's that?
不知道 没觉得朋友有什么用
I don't know, I just never really saw the use.
那你平时都跟谁玩啊
Well, who are you going to play with otherwise?
列侬和麦卡尼在学校就是好哥们儿 对吧
Lennon and McCartney, they were school friends, am I right?
乔.琼斯拿钵砸查理.帕克之前 查理也没有朋友
Charlie Parker didn't know anybody 'til Joe Jones threw a cymbal at his head.
所以在你看来那就算成功？
So that's your idea of success, huh?
我觉得成为20世纪最伟大的音乐家在谁看来都算成功
I think being the greatest musician of the 20th century is anybody's idea of success.
酗酒吸毒34岁就家破人亡在我看来可不算成功
Dying broke and drunk and full of heroin at the age of 34 is not exactly my idea of success.
我宁愿酗酒吸毒 34岁就家破人亡 成为人们晚餐桌上的话题
I'd rather die drunk, broke at 34 and have people at a dinner table talk about me
也不愿意腰缠万贯满面红光的活到90岁 但是没人记得我
than live to be rich and sober at 90 and nobody remembered who I was.
但是你的朋友记得你 那才是重点
Ah, but your friends will remember you, that's the point.
我们谁都不是查理.帕克的朋友 那才是重点
None of us were friends with Charlie Parker. That's the point.
特拉维斯和达斯汀 朋友很多 目标也很多
Travis and Dustin? They have plenty of friends and plenty of purpose.
嗯当学生会主席在合适不过了
I'm sure they'll make great school board presidents someday.
原来你就是跟这个过不去么？你觉得你比我们强？
Oh, that's what this is all about? You think you're better than us?
反应挺快的啊 模联出来的？
You catch on quick. Are you in Model UN?
听好了安德鲁 你觉得卡尔顿橄榄球队是个笑话？
I got a reply for you, Andrew. You think Carleton football's a joke?
跟我们来一场
Come play with us.
4个字 你下辈子都进不了NFL
Four words you will never hear from the NFL.
谁想吃甜点？
Who wants dessert?
进林肯中心呢？
And from Lincoln Center?
好了今天就到这了
Alright guys, get out of here.
走前别玩了拿新谱子
Pick up the new chart by the door on your way out.
今晚9点整排练 在那之前练好了来
Rehearsal 9PM sharp tonight, that's how long you have till then to learn it.
内曼 过来下
Neyman, just come over here.
看到标的节奏了么？
See the tempo marking on there?
四分音符速度330
Quarter note equals 330
双倍摇摆
That is a double-time swing.
你就是靠这个进来的对吧
That's what got you in here right?
是啊
Oh yeah.
和你一样 我最近碰到了另外一个小孩
I recently stumbled across another kid
在排练室练双倍摇摆
In the practice room working on his double time swing.
所以我想给他个机会
So I'm gonna give him another shot.
我来晚了？
Am I late?
来的刚好
Perfect timing.
进来吧康纳利
Come on in Connelly
你俩认识吧？
You two know each other right?
嗯嗯 拿苏乐队
Yeah, yeah, Nassau band.
你好啊安德鲁
Hey, what's up Andrew.
嗯 康纳利 我刚让内曼当临时核心
Now Connelly I've made Neyman a temporary core.
但是马上就要比赛了 我只想保证一切都达到最高水准
But with this competition coming up I just wannna make very sure this chart's in the best shape it can be.
是这个吧？
Yeah it's the one right here right?
我今天早上给他的谱子
I gave Connelly the chart this morning.
现在给你俩个机会一起试试吧
All you need to do now is to just give both of you a crack at it, alright?
内曼你先上吧 从头开始
So Neyman go ahead jump on the kit we'll take it from the top.
好吧
Ok.
别担心鼓点 把住节奏就好
I don't want you to worry about the hits right now, just tempo.
好
Ok?
准别好了？
All set?
节奏有点问题
Not quite my tempo.
-康纳利 -没事让我再试一遍
-Connelly? -Ok, I'll take.. from the top.
-我能...  -不用了 让康纳利来吧
-I can do... -No, we'll go with Connelly now.
借用下？
Hey do you mind?
-准备好了？ -嗯
-Ok? -Yeah
漂亮！
Perfect Connelly
这就是我喜欢音乐室乐队的原因之一
See this to me is the beauty of Studio Band.
一个替补走进来 谁能想到马上就成新核心了？
You walk in here an alternate, who knows you could be the new core.
靠你是逗我呢么
Oh my god, are you serious?
就这玩意儿？
That shit?
弗莱彻
Fletcher.
谢了哥们
Thanks man.
别理弗莱彻 他光打雷不下雨
Don't worry about Fletcher, he's more bark than bite.
-Hey 我能打好这曲子  -现在不是时候
-Hey look, I can play these charts.  -Now's not the time.
-我能打  -我说了不是时候！
-I can play. -I said not now!
你要真他妈想当核心 靠本事挣去
If you want the fucking part, earn it.
我直说了吧
I'm just gonna lay it out there.
我觉得我们不应该再在一起了
This is why I don't think that we shouldn't be together.
我想了很久
And I thought about it a lot.
接下来会是这样的：
And this is what's gonna happen, ok?
我会一直追求我所追求的
I'm gonna keep pursuing what I'm pursuing
所以在练鼓上花的时间会越来越多
And because I'm doing that it's gonna take more and more of my time
能陪你的时间只会越来越少
And I'm not gonna be able to spend so much time with you.
而当我陪你的时候满脑子全是练鼓
And when I do spend time with you, I'll be thinking about drumming.
爵士和乐谱
I'll be thinking about Jazz and my charts and all that.
所以你迟早会讨厌我
And because of that you're gonna start to resent me.
之后你会抱怨让我腾出更多时间来陪你
And you're gonna tell me to ease up drumming, spend more time with you
因为你会越来越没安全感
because you're not feeling importrant
但我做不到
And I'm not gonna be able to do that.
而且只要你一开始说“少打点鼓”我肯定会开始烦你
And I'll just start to resent you for even asking me to stop drumming.
再然后就只能彼此憎恶了
And we'll just start to hate each other.
那就不好看了
And it's gonna get very... it's gonna be ugly.
所以说长痛不如短痛 还是现在就分手吧
And so... for those reasons, I'd rather just break it off clean.
因为我想更优秀
Cuz I wanna be great.
你还不优秀么？
And you're not?
我想成为最伟大的之一
I wanna be one of the greats.
但有我你就成不了？
And I'll stop you from doing that?
嗯
Yeah.
你知道有我你就成不了 你就这么确定这是既定事实么？
You know I'll stop you from doing that. You know that for a fact.
是的
Yes.
即使我几乎没怎么见到过你
And I barely see you anyway
-嗯  -好不容易见到了你也爱理不理的
-Yeah -And when I did see you you treated me like shit
因为我是个不知道自己要什么的女孩
because I'm just some girl who doesn't know what she wants
你有理想 你能成功 我只会被人遗忘
And you have a path, and you're going to be great, and I'm gonna be forgotten
所以你不可能有空陪我
And therefore, you won't be able to give me the time and day
因为你有更宏远的追求
because you have bigger things to pursue.
跟我想说的一模一样
That's exactly my point.
你他妈的有病么？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
你说的对 我们不该再在一起了
You're right, we should not be dating.
不用了谢谢
I'm ok, thanks.
操！操！
Fuck! Fuck!
操你妈的傻逼！
Fucking piece of shit!
操你妈的！操！
Fuck you! Fuck!
抱歉 新来了个鼓手
Sorry we have a new player
瑞安.康纳利
Ryan Connelly
不好意思
I'm sorry.
先把乐器放一边吧
Can you just... put your instruments down, for a minute?
听一分钟
Just listen for a minute.
六年前
Six years ago
我在练琴室碰到了一个正在调音阶的孩子
I came across a kid in the practice room working on his scales
刚上大二
He was early second year
怀揣着希望来到谢尔佛
and he started in Shaffer with a lot of hope
和你们一样
Like all you guys.
但事实是... 他差点都没能进来
but the truth was... He barely squeezed in to begin with and..
那段日子对他很痛苦
He was really struggling.
老师们都劝他 或许你真的不是搞音乐的料
The faculty were all telling him, maybe this isn't for you.
但他们没有看到我所看到的
But they didn't see what I saw.
那个瘦小的、担惊受怕的男孩
That scared, skinny kid,
因为音阶对不准而咒骂自己
cursing himself because he couldn't get the scales right.
我看到的 是他内心无法遏制的冲劲
I saw a drive in him.
于是我把他招进了音乐室乐队
And I put him in Studio Band.
等到毕业时
When he graduated
成了林肯中心的三席号手
made him the third trumpet in Lincoln Center.
一年之后他已经是首席了
A year later he was the first.
你们现在听到的就是他
And that's what you're listening to now.
他的名字叫肖恩.凯西
His name was Sean Casey.
今天早上我得知 肖恩...
I found out this morning that... Sean
昨天出车祸...
died yesterday.
死了
in a car accident.
我只想...
And I just...
让你们知道 他是一个动人出色的乐手
want you guys to know he was a beautiful player.
我只是觉得应该让你们知道
I just thought you should know.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好了
Ok.
开工吧
Let's get to work, how about...
Caravan  105小节
Caravan, bar 105
一 二 走
One and two and
康纳利 你那有点问题
It's not... not quite right Connelly
让内曼试试吧
I'd like to try Neyman on this.
或许现在是内曼挣回核心的时候了
Maybe now is the time for Neyman to earn the part
一 二 走
One and two and
嗯 还是算了吧
No, I guess not.
坦纳
Tanner
一 二 走
One and two and
操你妈的！
Motherfucker!
康纳利给我滚上去！
Connelly get your ass back on the kit
今晚你们仨娘炮里出不了一个能按节奏打的咱就不回家了
We'll stay here for as long as it takes till one of faggots can play in time.
一 二 走
One and two and
看来得通宵了 内曼
looks like it'll be all night. Neyman.
一 二 走
One and two and
妈逼节奏不对！
Not my fucking tempo!
对不住了大家 要让你们这么等着
Sorry guys, hate to put you through this
如果你要上大号喝咖啡什么的
If you need to fucking take a dump or get a coffee whatever
最好现在去
now might be a good time
找不到能按节奏打的鼓手前谁都别想回家
because we're gonna stay here until I find a drummer who can fucking play in time
先给你们道个歉
I apologize to the musicians.
真的 休息10分钟 20分钟 1个小时
Seriously, take ten, twenty, a fucking hour
听见了么小逼崽子？
You hear me cocksuckers?
你们最好趁早给我打出完美的400拍
You better start shitting me perfect 400
康纳利给我滚到鼓架上
Connelly get your fucking ass back on the kit
你就只能打这么快了么 屁用没有的犹太逼
This is really the fastest you can play, you worthless himey fuck?
怪不得你妈不要你了 滚一边去
No wonder mommy ran out on you. Get off the fucking kit.
有请上西区的基佬先生
And here comes Mr. Gay pride of the Upper Western side himself
可惜这不是贝蒂.米勒的演唱会 我们不送火焰冰激凌和大都会鸡尾酒
Unfortunately this is not a Bette Midler Concert, we'll not be serving Cosmopolitan and Baked Alaska
所以撸你男朋友的时候有多快你就给我打多快
So just play faster than you give fucking hand jobs, will you please?
一 二 一 二
One two one two
差的太他妈远了
Not even fucking close
轮到爱尔兰猪登场了
Let's go with the Irish mick fucking paddy-cracker now
你真他妈太像小妖精了
You... you actually do look quite a bit like a leprechaun
现在开始我就叫你爱尔兰妞吧
I'll start calling you Flannery
滚！
Get off!
你他妈看屁呢 地上又没金子
What the fuck you looking... there's not a pot of gold down there
哦调座位啊 你逗我？
Oh adjusting the seat, really?!
折腾半天问题就是座位高度是么
That's been your fucking problem the whole time? The seat height?
那现在你能打好了对吧？
So now you have it right?
走
Go.
扯你妈蛋！傻逼！
Bullshit! Fuck you!
内曼
Neyman.
或许 终于是时候画上个句号了 你说呢
Maybe, it's time to finally bring this home, what do you say?
给我看看
Show me.
别慢下来
Don't slow down!
快点
Pick it up!
再快点！
Faster!
别停！
Keep playing!
内曼
Neyman
你挣回核心了
You earned the part.
替补们 给我把鼓架上的血擦干净
Alternates, you wanna clean the blood off my drum set?
好了 可以开始了
Ok, we can start now.
下午5点到场  Dunellen市里
5pm call tomorrow, in Dunnellen
给你自己最少留2小时的时间出发
Give yourself at least two hours to get there from the city this time alright?
记得留大巴收据
Save your travel receipts.
或者扔了 关我屁事
Or no, I don't give a shit.
Dunellen比赛日
抱歉打扰下 您知道出租车在哪儿么？
Excuse me, do you know where the cabs are?
-你得打电话叫  -他们说出租车在这接人？
-You have to call the cabs. -I konw, they say the cabs suppose to be right here?
没有啊 你得打电话叫才行 要等很久
No you gotta call them, it'll take forever.
算了租车的地方在哪儿？
Ok how do I get the Hardrove?
快点快点 别关门 别关门
Come on please, come on, you're still open! You're still open!
快点 快
Come on, come on!
-你好? -你他妈跑哪儿去了？5点就要开始了
-Yeah hello? -Where the fuck are you man? Call time is 5
我知道我知道 马上到了 马上到了
I know, I know, I'm almost there. I'm almost there man. I'm right there.
-还有20分钟就要上台了  -我知道还有20分钟上台
-We're on stage in 20 -I know we're on stage in 20
-弗莱彻已经让康纳利开始热身了  -康你妈纳利!
-Fletcher got Connelly warming up... -God fucking damnit!
你告诉那臭婊子我马上就到
You just tell that little fucking redhead I'm gonna be there ok?
操
Fuck
Hey 不好意思来晚了
Hey, Sorry I'm late.
哦亲爱的 难得你挤出时间过来了
Glad you finished on your busy schedule, darling.
我知道 对不起 我来了准备上场吧
I know. Look, I'm sorry, but I'm here man, ready to go.
今天康纳利是核心
Connelly's playing the part.
去他妈的康纳利核心
Like fucking hell he's playing my part.
你他妈再给我说一遍？
What the fuck did you just say to me?
我是核心
It's my part.
核心是我的 我想给谁就给谁
It's my part, and I decide who to lend it to.
一般会给带鼓槌的人
Usually to somebody that has fucking sticks.
我忘车里了 马上回来
I left in the car, I'll be right back
-5分钟  -已经开始热身了
-Take me 5 minutes. -I'm warming up the band now.
-我就不能用下瑞安的鼓槌么.. -内曼 核心不是你了
-Look I can use Ryan's sticks -Neyman you lost the fucking part
操怎么就不是我了 你不能这么干！
No I didn't, look you can't fucking do this to me!
-不能？！ -不能！
-Can't?! -Yeah!
什么时候轮到你他妈来教育我能干什么不能干什么了？
When did you become a fucking expert on what I can or cannot do?
平胸柴火妞
You fucking weepy-willow shit sack?
核心是我挣来的
I earned that part.
你什么都没挣过 我操你他妈真是个自以为是的贱逼
You never earned anything. God you're a self-righteous prick
你当上核心全是因为你弄丢了谱子
The only reason you are a fucking core is because you misplaced folder.
你能进音乐室乐队全是以为你在拿苏的时候
The only reason you're in Studio Band to begin with is because I told you
我就清清楚楚告诉你我要找的是什么
exactly what I'd be asking for in Nassau
-我错了么？ -没
-Am I wrong?  -Yeah
-我能进音乐室乐队 是因为... -你就认了不行么
-I'm in Studio Band, cause I'm the.. -Why don't you just back off?!
滚你妈的 老老实实给我翻乐谱去小婊子
Hey you, fuck off Johnny Utah, turn my pages bitch!
Hey 我他妈想什么时候让你滚你就得滚
Hey, I can cut you any fucking time I want.
你离不开我
You wouldn't cut me by now.
你试试看啊软逼！
Try me you fucking weasel!
5点半 还剩整整11分钟 我的乐队就要上台了
At 5.30, that's exactly 11 minutes, my band is on stage.
那之前要是你没有带着鼓槌回来
If your ass is not on that stool with your own fucking sticks in hand
或者你他妈敢给我打错一拍
Or you make one fucking mistake
错一拍
One
我立马送你回拿苏给人翻谱子翻到毕业或者退学！
I'll drum your ass back to Nassau where you can turn pages untill you graduate or fucking drop off.
等你从谢尔佛滚蛋的时候你爸看着都比你成功
By the time you are done at Shaffer, you're gonna make daddy look like a fucking successful story
懂？
Got it?
或者 让康纳利做核心 你选
Or, we can let Johnny Utah play the part. You choose.
那是我的核心 我会上台的
It's my part, I'll be on your stage.
操... 十分钟！他妈的娘炮臭基佬
Fuck... you got ten minutes you fucking pathetic pansy-ass fruit-fuck
-给弗莱彻说我马上到  -怎么这么久啊你 要上台了都
-Hey tell Fletcher I'm coming. -What took you so long man, we're moving on stage right now.
我知道 车锁出了点问题
I know I got locked in my car. It's fine, I'm coming.
“200尺后左转”
"Left turn, 200 feet"
你开车呢？
Are you driving man?
-没 -那那是什么声音？
-No -What the hell is that noise?
靠你就告诉弗莱彻 我他妈马上到了!
Ok look why don't you just tell Fletcher, that I am coming you motherfucker!
你还好么？
Are you ok?
-你还好么？ -嗯我的鼓槌...
-Are you ok? -Yeah I gotta get my sticks.
别别别离车远点
No no no no, stay away from the car.
-我马上打911  -就几条街
-I'm calling 911, it's ok. -Just a couple more blocks.
先生，你不用...
Sir, you don't have to...
谢尔佛音乐学院 音乐室乐队
Shaffer Conservatory, Studio Band.
内曼你他妈想什么呢？
Neyman, what the fuck?
内曼
Neyman
你玩完了
You're done.
女士们先生们 我代表谢尔佛音乐学院表示歉意
Gentlemen and ladies, I apologize on behalf of Shaffer Conservatory.
我他妈弄死你！
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
别碰我！
Get off me!
Fuck you!
Fuck you Fletcher Fuck you!
操你妈的傻逼！
You fuck... piece of shit!
Fuck you!
你什么时候找到她的
When did you start talking to her?
我们是这周联系到你父亲的
Your father got contacted this week.
你知道肖恩.凯西么？
Does the name Sean Casey mean anything to you?
你知道他的死讯么？
Do you know about his death?
上个月他在公寓里上吊自尽了
Last month he hung himself in his apartment.
这和我有什么关系？
What's that have to do with me?
肖恩患有长期焦虑抑郁症
Sean suffered from anxiety and depression.
他母亲说这是在跟了弗莱彻之后开始的
His mother claimed this started during his time as Fletcher's student.
肖恩家里条件不是很好 他们也不打算提出诉讼
Now Caseys aren't wealthy, they don't wanna file suit
那...他们想要什么
So... what do they want?
确保不会再有学生遭到弗莱彻的虐待
To make sure that Terrance Fletcher's never allowed to do this to another student
...从谢尔佛开除...
他什么都没做
He didn't do anything.
你怎么了？都结束了好么
What's wrong with you? It's over ok?
他不会再出现在你生命中了 你为什么要放过他？
He's out of your life, why would you let him get away with what he did to you?
你觉得他的教学方式是否太过极端？
Would you characterize his conduct as extreme Andrew?
他是否有在精神上蓄意折磨你？
Did he ever intentionally inflict emotional distress?
这案子不会有公开听证会
This will not be a public hearing, you know?
弗莱彻永远不会知道是你说的
Fletcher will never know it was you who spoke up.
你为什么要逼我
Why would you do this to me?
你真以为我会让他这样折磨完我儿子后
Do you think that I would let him put my son through hell
大摇大摆走人么？
And just walk away scot-free?
你不知道这是我绝对无法容忍的么？
Don't you know I would never let that happen?
这世界上没有什么对我比你更重要的了
That there is nothing in the world more important to me than you?
你还不知道么？
Don't you know that?
安德鲁？
Andrew?
告诉我该怎么说吧
Just tell me what to say.
夏
-Hey 我给你壁橱里留了点零食  -我看到了
-Hi, and... I loaded your pantry with Gushers. -I saw that.
谢谢
Thanks
爵士现场... 特邀嘉宾：泰伦斯.弗莱彻
安德鲁
Andrew
Hey
不知道你听说了没
Don't know if you heard...
我不在谢尔佛了
I'm not in Shaffer any more.
嗯... 我听说了
Yeah I did hear that.
你辞职了？
Did you quit?
不是
Not exactly.
有和肖恩一届的学生家长...
Some parents got a kid from Sean Casey's year I think
说了些关于我的话
to say somethings about me.
我以为除了阿谀奉承意外 大家最多也就会说我比较神秘吧
Although why anybody would have anything other than peaches and cream to say about me is a mystery.
很好笑吧
That's a good laugh right?
-不好意思  -别 我懂
-I'm sorry. -No I get it.
我知道我树了不少敌
I know I've made enemies.
不过我还在指挥
I'm conducting though
今年的JVC音乐节请我回去了
They brought back JVC fest this year
过两周会带一支专业乐队去做开场表演
They got me opening in a couple of weeks with a pro band.
挺好的啊
That's great.
还行吧
It's alright.
说实话 我觉得人们...
Truth is, I don't think people...
根本不知道我在谢尔佛做的是什么
understood what it was I was doing at Shaffer.
我不是去指挥的
I wasn't there to conduct.
弱智也会摇摇胳膊控制节奏
Any fucking moron can wave his arms and keep people in tempo.
我是去逼他们突破自己的极限的
I was there to push people beyond what's expected of them
我相信...
I believe that is...
这是绝对不可或缺的
an absolute necessity.
不然只会浪费掉下一个路易.阿姆斯特朗
otherwise we're depriving the world the next Louie Armstrong
下一个查理.帕克
the next Charlie Parker.
我给你讲过那个查理.帕克怎样成为查理.帕克的故事吧
I told that story about how Charlie Parker became Charlie Parker
-乔.琼斯朝他脑袋上砸了个钵  -就是这样
-Jo Jones threw a cymbal at his head. -Exactly.
当时帕克还年轻 萨克斯吹的很好
Parker was a young kid. Pretty good on the sax.
一路拼到淘汰赛
Gets up to play in the cutting session
然后玩砸了
And he fucks it up.
乔.琼斯差点没把他脑袋削下来
And Jones nearly decapitates him for it.
回到后台受尽奚落
and he's laughed off-stage
那晚上哭着入睡 但第二天起来 他做了什么？
crie himself to sleep that night, but the next moring, what does he do?
练琴
he practices.
练琴 还是练琴 心中只有一个目标
and he practices and he practices, with one goal in mind
再也不能被任何人嘲笑
never to be laughed at again.
一年后他回到舞台上
And a year later he goes back to the Reno.
吹出了有史以来最他妈牛逼的独奏
And he steps up on that stage and he plays the best motherfucking solo the world has ever heard.
所以你想一下 如果琼斯只是说
So imagine if Jones just said.
“还可以查理”
"Well that's ok Charlie"
“挺好的 不错”
"That was alright, good job."
然后查理回去想
and Charlie thinks to himself
“操 老子吹的不错啊”
"Well, shit, I did a pretty good job."
再就没有后续了
End of story.
没有大鸟了
No bird.
对我来说那简直就是悲剧
That to me is an absolute tragedy.
但是现在大家就只想要这样
But that's just what the world wants now.
还都纳闷为什么爵士将死
People wonder why Jazz is dying
给你说吧哥们儿
I tell you man
你去看看每家星巴克里摆的爵士专辑就懂我意思了
Every Starbucks' Jazz album just proved my point, really.
英语里再没有哪两个字
There are no two words in English language
比“不错”更害人的了
more harmful than "good job".
那就没有个界限了么？
But is there a line?
比如... 你逼的太狠 下一个查理.帕克反而气馁退出了
You know maybe... you go to far, you discourage next Charlie Parker from ever becoming Charlie Parker?
不会的 怎么会？
No man, no.
因为下一个查理.帕克永远不会气馁
Because the next Charlie Parker would never be discouraged.
嗯
Yeah.
事实是
The truth is, Andrew
我从来没有过自己的查理.帕克
I never really had a Charlie Parker.
但我努力了
But I tried.
我他妈的是真努力了
I actually fucking tried.
这一点就已经比多数人走的远多了
And that's  more than most people ever do.
而我永远不会为自己怎样努力过而道歉
and I'll never apologize for how I tried.
嗯 回见了
Alright, see you later.
Hey 安德鲁
Hey Andrew
我不知道你会怎么想 但是...
Listen I have no idea how you gonna take this, but...
我带去JVC的这支乐队
the band I'm leading for JVC
鼓手还是差口气
The drummer's not cutting it.
懂我意思么？
You understand what I'm saying?
-不懂  -我用的都是音乐室乐队的曲目
-No. -I'm using the Studio Band playlist.
Caravan Whiplash
我得找个把谱子吃透的
I need somebody who really knows these charts.
瑞安.康纳利呢
What about Ryan Connelly?
他一直都是我用来激发你动力的而已
Ryan Connelly ever was to me is an incentive for you.
坦纳？
Tanner?
坦纳转学医了
Tanner switched to premed
应该是气馁了吧
Guess he got discouraged.
周末回去考虑考虑吧
Hey, take the weekend, think about it.
-你好？ -你好妮可 是安德鲁
-Hello? -Hey Nicole, it's Andrew.
-你好  -你好
-Hi -Hey
有一阵子...
Been a while since...
没跟你聊天了
I talked to you
嗯... 我就是想说...
Look...
真的对不起
I'm really sorry
我不是... 那个...
about everything, that's not.. not but.. I'm just
真的对不起
really sorry.
我其实... 我这周末有个演出
But anyway I got... I actually have this show this weekend
是叫... JVC 不知道你想不想来
It's a... JVC thing, I don't know maybe if you wanna go
在卡耐基剧院 演出完可以一起去吃个匹萨
it's in Carnegie Hall and.. we.. maybe get some like.. pizza afterwards
抱怨下学校里那点事... 什么的
like.. complain about our schools.. again.
那是... JV？
What... is that JV?
不是 是JVC 那个... 是爵士乐...啦
No it's JVC, it's like a.. it's Jazz... thing.
嗯... 我不知道哎
Ugh... I don't know if I can come.
我得问下我男朋友
I have to check with my boyfriend.
好吧
Ok
行
Yeah
我会问他的 但是我觉得他... 估计对爵士没什么兴趣
I'll check, but I don't know that... he's into Jazz, so...
嗯对 不是人人都喜欢的
Yeah I mean, not for everybody.
好吧 那就到时候见吧
Ok, well I guess maybe I'll see you guys there.
好
Ok.
好 拜
Ok, bye.
好了都听好了
Alright gangs, listen up.
对于那些第一次参加JVC的
Now for those of you who are new with this
...除了卡尔估计都是第一次吧
which looks like might be everybody except Karl
今晚可以改变你的人生
Tonight can change your life.
底下的观众一个电话
The folks out there make a phone call
你就能成蓝点唱片的签约乐手
You can be a blue note signee
EMC客户
An EMC client
林肯中心核心
A Lincoln Center core
但如果你玩砸了
On the other hand, if you drop the ball
就考虑换行吧
you might be looking for a new line of work because
因为这些人的另一个特点
the other thing about these cats is
是过目不忘
they never forget.
准备好了？
We all set?
好好玩吧
Alright, let's have fun.
你当我是傻逼么
You think I'm fucking stupid?
啊？
What?
我知道是你
I know it was you.
谢谢 女士们先生们
Thank you ladies and gentlemen
很荣幸能够为JVC做开场演出
We're very excited to be here kicking off the JVC festival this year
我是特伦斯.弗莱彻 这些是纽约最优秀的音乐家
I'm Terrance Fletcher, and these are some of the best musicans in New York
也就是全世界最优秀的音乐家
which means some of the best musicians in the world.
我们会演奏些之前的常规曲目但是首先为你们带来的
And we're gonna do some old standard for you but first
是一首出自蒂姆.西蒙尼的曲子
we're gonna start out with a new tone By Tim Simonec
叫做Upswinging
called Upswinging
你干嘛呢？！
What the fuck are you doing?!
打啊！
Come on!
嗯 看来你没这天分
Yeah I guess maybe you don't have it.
没事 回家吧
Come on, let's go home.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
等我提示！
I'll cue you in!
Caravan.
三 四
Three Four!
"FUCK YOU!"
我他妈把你眼球挖出来.
I'll gouge out your motherfucking eye.
安德鲁 你干嘛呢
Andrew what're you doing man?
等我提示
I'll cue you!
专供PlumYan欣赏版，我们都是爱电影爱音乐的好孩子